<article>
 <preamble> ACL2004-HEADLINE.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> Hybrid Headlines: Combining Topics and Sentence Compression  </titre>
 <auteur>      David Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Stacy President         Richard Schwartz  </auteur>
 <abstract> Abstract This paper presents Topiary, a headlinegeneration system that creates very short, informative summaries for news stories by combining sentence compression and unsupervised topic discovery. We will show that the combination of linguistically motivated sentence compression with statistically selected topic terms performs better than either alone, according to some automatic summary evaluation measures. In addition we describe experimental results establishing an appropriate extrinsic task on which to measure the effect of summarization on human performance. We demonstrate the usefulness of headlines in comparison to full texts in the context of this extrinsic task.   </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesSabine Bergler, René Witte, Michelle Khalife,Zhuoyan Li, and Frank Rudzicz. 2003. Usingknowledge-poor coreference resolution for text summarization. In Proceedings of the 2003 DocumentUnderstanding Conference, Draft Papers, pages 85–92, Edmonton, Candada.Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.2003a. Cross-language headline generation forhindi. ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP), 2:2.Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.2003b. Hedge trimmer: A parse-and-trim approachto headline generation. In Proceedings of the HLTNAACL 2003 Text Summarization Workshop, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada, pages 1–8.T. Euler. 2002. Tailoring text using topic words: Selection and compression. In Proceedings of 13thInternational Workshop on Database and ExpertSystems Applications (DEXA 2002), 2-6 September 2002, Aix-en-Provence, France, pages 215–222.IEEE Computer Society.Kevin Knight and Daniel Marcu. 2000. Statisticsbased summarization – step one: Sentence compression. In The 17th National Conference ofthe American Association for Artificial IntelligenceAAAI2000, Austin, Texas.David Lewis. 1992. An evaluation of phrasal and clustered representations on a text categorization task.In Proceedings of the 15th annual internationalACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval, pages 37–50, Copenhagen, Denmark.Chin-Yew Lin and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Automatic Evaluation of Summaries Using N-gram CoOccurrences Statistics. In Proceedings of the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Edmonton,Alberta.Ingrid Mårdh. 1980. Headlinese: On the Grammar ofEnglish Front Page Headlines. Malmo.S. Miller, M. Crystal, H. Fox, L. Ramshaw,R. Schwartz, R. Stone, and R. Weischedel. 1998.Algorithms that Learn to Extract Information; BBN:Description of the SIFT System as Used for MUC-7.In Proceedings of the MUC-7.K. Papineni, S. Roukos, T. Ward, and W. Zhu. 2002.Bleu: a Method for Automatic Evaluation of Machine Translation. In Proceedings of Association ofComputational Linguistics, Philadelphia, PA.R. Schwartz, T. Imai, F. Jubala, L. Nguyen, andJ. Makhoul. 1997. A maximum likelihood modelfor topic classification of broadcast news.InEurospeech-97, Rhodes, Greece.David Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Richard Schwartz, and StacyPresident. 2004. Headline evaluation experimentresults, umiacs-tr-2004-18. Technical report, University of Maryland Institute for Advanced Computing Studies, College Park, Maryland.Liang Zhou and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Headline summarization at isi. In Proceedings of the 2003 Document Understanding Conference, Draft Papers,pages 174–178, Edmonton, Candada. </biblio>
</article>
