<article>
 <preamble> B.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> A Scalable MMR Approach to Sentence Scoring for Multi-Document Update Summarization  </titre>
 <auteur>         Florian Boudin \ and Marc El-Bèze \                         Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno \,[  </auteur>
 <abstract> Abstract  redundancy with previously read documents (history) has to be removed from the extract. A natural way to go about update summarization would be extracting temporal tags (dates, elapsed times, temporal expressions...) (Mani and Wilson, 2000) or to automatically construct the timeline from documents (Swan and Allan, 2000). These temporal marks could be used to focus extracts on the most recently written facts. However, most recently written facts are not necessarily new facts. Machine Reading (MR) was used by (Hickl et al., 2007) to construct knowledge representations from clusters of documents. Sentences containing “new” information (i.e. that could not be inferred by any previously considered document) are selected to generate summary. However, this highly efficient approach (best system in DUC 2007 update) requires large linguistic resources. (Witte et al., 2007) propose a rule-based system based on fuzzy coreference cluster graphs. Again, this approach requires to manually write the sentence ranking scheme. Several strategies remaining on post-processing redundancy removal techniques have been suggested. Extracts constructed from history were used by (Boudin and TorresMoreno, 2007) to minimize history’s redundancy. (Lin et al., 2007) have proposed a modified Maximal Marginal Relevance (MMR) (Carbonell and Goldstein, 1998) re-ranker during sentence selection, constructing the summary by incrementally re-ranking sentences. In this paper, we propose a scalable sentence scoring method for update summarization derived from MMR. Motivated by the need for relevant novelty, candidate sentences are selected according to a combined criterion of query relevance and dissimilarity with previously read sentences. The rest of the paper is organized as follows. Section 2  We present S MMR, a scalable sentence scoring method for query-oriented update summarization. Sentences are scored thanks to a criterion combining query relevance and dissimilarity with already read documents (history). As the amount of data in history increases, non-redundancy is prioritized over query-relevance. We show that S MMR achieves promising results on the DUC 2007 update corpus.  1   </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesYe, S., L. Qiu, T.S. Chua, and M.Y. Kan. 2005. NUSat DUC 2005: Understanding documents via concept links. In Document Understanding Conference(DUC).Boudin, F. and J.M. Torres-Moreno. 2007. A Cosine Maximization-Minimization approach for UserOriented Multi-Document Update Summarization.In Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing(RANLP), pages 81–87.Carbonell, J. and J. Goldstein. 1998. The use of MMR,diversity-based reranking for reordering documentsand producing summaries. In 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval, pages 335–336.ACM Press New York, NY, USA.26 </biblio>
</article>
