<article>
 <preamble> compression_phrases_Prog-Linear-jair.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research 31 (2008) 399-429   </titre>
 <auteur> Edinburgh EH8 9LW, UK  </auteur>
 <abstract> Abstract Sentence compression holds promise for many applications ranging from summarization to subtitle generation. Our work views sentence compression as an optimization problem and uses integer linear programming (ILP) to infer globally optimal compressions in the presence of linguistically motivated constraints. We show how previous formulations of sentence compression can be recast as ILPs and extend these models with novel global constraints. Experimental results on written and spoken texts demonstrate improvements over state-of-the-art models.   </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesAho, A. V., & Ullman, J. D. (1969). Syntax directed translations and the pushdown assembler. Journal of Computer and System Sciences, 3, 37–56.Bangalore, S., Rambow, O., & Whittaker, S. (2000). Evaluation metrics for generation.In Proceedings of the first International Conference on Natural Language Generation,pp. 1–8, Mitzpe Ramon, Israel.Barzilay, R., & Lapata, M. (2006). Aggregation via set partitioning for natural languagegeneration. In Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of theNorth American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 359–366, New York, NY, USA.Bramsen, P., Deshpande, P., Lee, Y. K., & Barzilay, R. (2006). Inducing temporal graphs.In Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural LanguageProcessing, pp. 189–198, Sydney, Australia.Briscoe, E. J., & Carroll, J. (2002). Robust accurate statistical annotation of general text. InProceedings of the Third International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, pp. 1499–1504, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria.Charniak, E. (2000). A maximum-entropy-inspired parser. In Proceedings of the 1st NorthAmerican Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 132–139, Seattle, WA, USA.Clarke, J., & Lapata, M. (2006). Models for sentence compression: A comparison acrossdomains, training requirements and evaluation measures. In Proceedings of the 21stInternational Conference on Computational Linguistics and 44th Annual Meeting ofthe Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 377–384, Sydney, Australia.Clarkson, P., & Rosenfeld, R. (1997). Statistical language modeling using the CMU–Cambridge toolkit. In Proceedings of Eurospeech’97, pp. 2707–2710, Rhodes, Greece.426Global Inference for Sentence CompressionCormen, T. H., Leiserson, C. E., & Rivest, R. L. (1992). Intoduction to Algorithms. TheMIT Press.Corston-Oliver, S. (2001). Text Compaction for Display on Very Small Screens. In Proceedings of the Workshop on Automatic Summarization at the 2nd Meeting of the NorthAmerican Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 89–98, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.Crammer, K., & Singer, Y. (2003). Ultraconservative online algorithms for multiclass problems. Journal of Machine Learning Research, 3, 951–991.Dantzig, G. B. (1963). Linear Programming and Extensions. Princeton University Press,Princeton, NJ, USA.Denis, P., & Baldridge, J. (2007). Joint determination of anaphoricity and coreferenceresolution using integer programming. In Human Language Technologies 2007: TheConference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics; Proceedings of the Main Conference, pp. 236–243, Rochester, NY.Dras, M. (1999). Tree Adjoining Grammar and the Reluctant Paraphrasing of Text. Ph.D.thesis, Macquarie University.Galley, M., & McKeown, K. (2007). Lexicalized markov grammars for sentence compression.In In Proceedings of the North American Chapter of the Association for ComputationalLinguistics, pp. 180–187, Rochester, NY, USA.Gomory, R. E. (1960). Solving linear programming problems in integers. In Bellman,R., & Hall, M. (Eds.), Combinatorial analysis, Proceedings of Symposia in AppliedMathematics, Vol. 10, Providence, RI, USA.Grefenstette, G. (1998). Producing Intelligent Telegraphic Text Reduction to Provide anAudio Scanning Service for the Blind. In Hovy, E., & Radev, D. R. (Eds.), Proceedingsof the AAAI Symposium on Intelligent Text Summarization, pp. 111–117, Stanford,CA, USA.Hori, C., & Furui, S. (2004). Speech summarization: an approach through word extractionand a method for evaluation. IEICE Transactions on Information and Systems, E87D (1), 15–25.Jing, H. (2000). Sentence reduction for automatic text summarization. In Proceedings ofthe 6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference, pp. 310–315, Seattle,WA,USA.Knight, K., & Marcu, D. (2002). Summarization beyond sentence extraction: a probabilisticapproach to sentence compression. Artificial Intelligence, 139 (1), 91–107.Land, A. H., & Doig, A. G. (1960). An automatic method for solving discrete programmingproblems. Econometrica, 28, 497–520.Lin, C.-Y. (2003). Improving summarization performance by sentence compression — a pilotstudy. In Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Information Retrieval withAsian Languages, pp. 1–8, Sapporo, Japan.Lin, D. (2001). LaTaT: Language and text analysis tools. In Proceedings of the first HumanLanguage Technology Conference, pp. 222–227, San Francisco, CA, USA.427Clarke & LapataMarciniak, T., & Strube, M. (2005). Beyond the pipeline: Discrete optimization in NLP. InProceedings of the Ninth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning,pp. 136–143, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.McDonald, R. (2006). Discriminative sentence compression with soft syntactic constraints.In Proceedings of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association forComputational Linguistics, Trento, Italy.McDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005a). Flexible text segmentation with structured multilabel classification. In Proceedings of Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pp.987–994, Vancouver, BC, Canada.McDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005b). Online large-margin training of dependency parsers. In 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for ComputationalLinguistics, pp. 91–98, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.Nemhauser, G. L., & Wolsey, L. A. (1988). Integer and Combinatorial Optimization. WileyInterscience series in discrete mathematicals and opitmization. Wiley, New York, NY,USA.Nguyen, M. L., Shimazu, A., Horiguchi, S., Ho, T. B., & Fukushi, M. (2004). Probabilisticsentence reduction using support vector machines. In Proceedings of the 20th international conference on Computational Linguistics, pp. 743–749, Geneva, Switzerland.Press, W. H., Teukolsky, S. A., Vetterling, W. T., & Flannery, B. P. (1992). NumericalRecipes in C: The Art of Scientific Computing. Cambridge University Press, NewYork, NY, USA.Punyakanok, V., Roth, D., Yih, W., & Zimak, D. (2004). Semantic role labeling via integer linear programming inference. In Proceedings of the International Conference onComputational Linguistics, pp. 1346–1352, Geneva, Switzerland.Riedel, S., & Clarke, J. (2006). Incremental integer linear programming for non-projectivedependency parsing. In Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods inNatural Language Processing, pp. 129–137, Sydney, Australia.Riezler, S., King, T. H., Crouch, R., & Zaenen, A. (2003). Statistical sentence condensationusing ambiguity packing and stochastic disambiguation methods for lexical-functionalgrammar. In Human Language Technology Conference and the 3rd Meeting of theNorth American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 118–125, Edmonton, Canada.Roark, B. (2001). Probabilistic top-down parsing and language modeling. ComputationalLinguistics, 27 (2), 249–276.Roth, D. (1998). Learning to resolve natural language ambiguities: A unified approach. InIn Proceedings of the 15th of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence, pp.806–813, Madison, WI, USA.Roth, D., & Yih, W. (2004). A linear programming formulation for global inference innatural language tasks. In Proceedings of the Annual Conference on ComputationalNatural Language Learning, pp. 1–8, Boston, MA, USA.428Global Inference for Sentence CompressionRoth, D., & Yih, W. (2005). Integer linear programming inference for conditional randomfields. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning, pp. 737–744, Bonn.Sarawagi, S., & Cohen, W. W. (2004). Semi-markov conditional random fields for information extraction. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, Vancouver,BC, Canada.Shieber, S., & Schabes, Y. (1990). Synchronous tree-adjoining grammars. In Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, pp. 253–258,Helsinki, Finland.Turner, J., & Charniak, E. (2005). Supervised and unsupervised learning for sentencecompression. In Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 290–297, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.Vandeghinste, V., & Pan, Y. (2004). Sentence compression for automated subtitling: Ahybrid approach. In Marie-Francine Moens, S. S. (Ed.), Text Summarization BranchesOut: Proceedings of the ACL-04 Workshop, pp. 89–95, Barcelona, Spain.Williams, H. P. (1999). Model Building in Mathematical Programming (4th edition). Wiley.Winston, W. L., & Venkataramanan, M. (2003). Introduction to Mathematical Programming: Applications and Algorithms (4th edition). Duxbury.Zajic, D., Door, B. J., Lin, J., & Schwartz, R. (2007). Multi-candidate reduction: Sentencecompression as a tool for document summarization tasks. Information ProcessingManagement Special Issue on Summarization, 43 (6), 1549–1570.429 </biblio>
</article>
