<article>
 <preamble> marcu_statistics_sentence_pass_one.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> Statistics-Based Summarization — Step One: Sentence Compression
 </titre>
 <auteur>                                            Kevin Knight and Daniel Marcu  </auteur>
 <abstract> Abstract When humans produce summaries of documents, they do not simply extract sentences and concatenate them. Rather, they create new sentences that are grammatical, that cohere with one another, and that capture the most salient pieces of information in the original document. Given that large collections of text/abstract pairs are available online, it is now possible to envision algorithms that are trained to mimic this process. In this paper, we focus on sentence compression, a simpler version of this larger challenge. We aim to achieve two goals simultaneously: our compressions should be grammatical, and they should retain the most important pieces of information. These two goals can conﬂict. We devise both noisy-channel and decision-tree approaches to the problem, and we evaluate results against manual compressions and a simple baseline.   </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesBarzilay, R.; McKeown, K.; and Elhadad, M. 1999.Information fusion in the context of multi-documentsummarization. In Proceedings of the 37th AnnualMeeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL–99), 550–557.Berger, A., and Laﬀerty, J. 1999. Information retrievalas statistical translation. In Proceedings of the 22ndConference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR–99), 222–229.Brown, P.; Della Pietra, S.; Della Pietra, V.; and Mercer, R. 1993. The mathematics of statistical machine translation: Parameter estimation. Computational Linguistics 19(2):263–311.Church, K. 1988. A stochastic parts program and nounphrase parser for unrestricted text. In Proceedings ofthe Second Conference on Applied Natural LanguageProcessing, 136–143.Collins, M. 1997. Three generative, lexicalized models for statistical parsing. In Proceedings of the 35thAnnual Meeting of the Association for ComputationalLinguistics (ACL–97), 16–23.Grefenstette, G. 1998. Producing intelligent telegraphic text reduction to provide an audio scanningservice for the blind. In Working Notes of the AAAISpring Symposium on Intelligent Text Summarization,111–118.Jelinek, F. 1997. Statistical Methods for Speech Recognition. The MIT Press.Jing, H., and McKeown, K. 1999. The decompositionof human-written summary sentences. In Proceedingsof the 22nd Conference on Research and Developmentin Information Retrieval (SIGIR–99).Knight, K., and Graehl, J. 1998. Machine transliteration. Computational Linguistics 24(4):599–612.Langkilde, I. 2000. Forest-based statistical sentencegeneration. In Proceedings of the 1st Annual Meetingof the North American Chapter of the Association forComputational Linguistics.Linke-Ellis, N. 1999. Closed captioning in America: Looking beyond compliance. In Proceedings ofthe TAO Workshop on TV Closed Captions for thehearing impaired people, 43–59.Magerman, D. 1995. Statistical decision-tree modelsfor parsing. In Proceedings of the 33rd Annual Meetingof the Association for Computational Linguistics, 276–283.Mani, I., and Maybury, M., eds. 1999. Advances inAutomatic Text Summarization. The MIT Press.Mani, I.; Gates, B.; and Bloedorn, E. 1999. Improvingsummaries by revising them. In Proceedings of the 37thAnnual Meeting of the Association for ComputationalLinguistics, 558–565.McKeown, K.; Klavans, J.; Hatzivassiloglou, V.;Barzilay, R.; and Eskin, E. 1999. Towards multidocument summarization by reformulation: Progress andprospects. In Proceedings of the Sixteenth NationalConference on Artiﬁcial Intelligence (AAAI–99).Quinlan, J. 1993. C4.5: Programs for Machine Learning. San Mateo, CA: Morgan Kaufmann Publishers.Robert-Ribes, J.; Pfeiﬀer, S.; Ellison, R.; and Burnham, D. 1999. Semi-automatic captioning of TV programs, an Australian perspective. In Proceedings ofthe TAO Workshop on TV Closed Captions for thehearing impaired people, 87–100.Witbrock, M., and Mittal, V.1999.Ultrasummarization: A statistical approach to generatinghighly condensed non-extractive summaries. In Proceedings of the 22nd International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR’99), Poster Session, 315–316. </biblio>
</article>
