<article>
 <preamble> mikheev.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> Periods, Capitalized Words, etc.
 </titre>
 <auteur> tion: sentence boundary disambiguation, disambiguation of capitalized words in positions where capitalization is expected, and identification of abbreviations. As opposed to the two dominant  </auteur>
 <abstract>  </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesAberdeen, John S., John D. Burger, David S.Day, Lynette Hirschman, PatriciaRobinson, and Marc Vilain. 1995. “Mitre:Description of the alembic system usedfor MUC-6.” In Proceedings of the SixthMessage Understanding Conference (MUC-6),Columbia, Maryland, November. MorganKaufmann.Baldwin, Breck, Christine Doran, JeffreyReynar, Michael Niv, Bangalore Srinivas,and Mark Wasson. 1997. “EAGLE: Anextensible architecture for generallinguistic engineering.” In Proceedings ofComputer-Assisted Information Searching on316Internet (RIAO ’97), Montreal, June.Baum, Leonard E. and Ted Petrie. 1966.Statistical inference for probabilisticfunctions of finite Markov chains. Annalsof Mathematical Statistics 37:1559–1563.Bikel, Daniel, Scott Miller, RichardSchwartz, and Ralph Weischedel. 1997.“Nymble: A high performance learningname-finder.” In Proceedings of the FifthConference on Applied Natural LanguageProcessing (ANLP’97), pages 194–200.Washington, D.C., Morgan Kaufmann.Brill, Eric. 1995a. Transformation-basederror-driven learning and naturallanguage parsing: A case study inpart-of-speech tagging. ComputationalLinguistics 21(4):543–565.Brill, Eric. 1995b. “Unsupervised learning ofdisambiguation rules for part of speechtagging.” In David Yarovsky and KennethChurch, editors, Proceedings of the ThirdWorkshop on Very Large Corpora, pages1–13, Somerset, New Jersey. Associationfor Computational Linguistics.Burnage, Gavin. 1990. CELEX: A Guide forUsers. Centre for Lexical Information,Nijmegen, Netherlands.MikheevChinchor, Nancy. 1998. “Overview ofMUC-7.” In Seventh Message UnderstandingConference (MUC-7): Proceedings of aConference Held in Fairfax, April. MorganKaufmann.Church, Kenneth. 1988. “A stochastic partsprogram and noun-phrase parser forunrestricted text.” In Proceedings of theSecond ACL Conference on Applied NaturalLanguage Processing (ANLP’88), pages136–143, Austin, Texas.Church, Kenneth. 1995. “One term or two?”In SIGIR’95, Proceedings of the 18th AnnualInternational ACM SIGIR Conference onResearch and Development in InformationRetrieval, pages 310–318, Seattle,Washington, July. ACM Press.Clarkson, Philip and Anthony J. Robinson.1997. “Language model adaptation usingmixtures and an exponentially decayingcache.” In Proceedings IEEE InternationalConference on Speech and Signal Processing,Munich, Germany.Cucerzan, Silviu and David Yarowsky. 1999.“Language independent named entityrecognition combining morphological andcontextual evidence.” In Proceedings ofJoint SIGDAT Conference on EMNLP andVLC.Francis, W. Nelson and Henry Kucera. 1982.Frequency Analysis of English Usage: Lexiconand Grammar. Houghton Mifflin, NewYork.Gale, William, Kenneth Church, and DavidYarowsky. 1992. “One sense perdiscourse.” In Proceedings of the FourthDARPA Speech and Natural LanguageWorkshop, pages 233–237.Grefenstette, Gregory and Pasi Tapanainen.1994. “What is a word, what is asentence? Problems of tokenization.” InThe Proceedings of Third Conference onComputational Lexicography and TextResearch (COMPLEX’94), Budapest,Hungary.Krupka, George R. and Kevin Hausman.1998. Isoquest Inc.: Description of thenetowl extractor system as used forMUC-7. In Proceedings of the SeventhMessage Understanding Conference (MUC-7),Fairfax, VA. Morgan Kaufmann.Kuhn, Roland and Renato de Mori. 1998. Acache-based natural language model forspeech recognition. IEEE Transactions onPattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence12:570–583.Kupiec, Julian. 1992. Robust part-of-speechtagging using a hidden Markov model.Computer Speech and Language.Mani, Inderjeet and T. Richard MacMillan.1995. “Identifying unknown properPeriods, Capitalized Words, etc.names in newswire text.” In B. Boguraevand J. Pustejovsky, editors, CorpusProcessing for Lexical Acquisition. MIT Press,Cambridge, Massachusetts, pages 41–59.Marcus, Mitchell, Mary Ann Marcinkiewicz,and Beatrice Santorini. 1993. Building alarge annotated corpus of English: ThePenn treebank. Computational Linguistics19(2):313–329.Mikheev, Andrei. 1997. Automatic ruleinduction for unknown word guessing.Computational Linguistics 23(3):405–423.Mikheev, Andrei. 1999. A knowledge-freemethod for capitalized worddisambiguation. In Proceedings of the 37thConference of the Association forComputational Linguistics (ACL’99), pages159–168, University of Maryland, CollegePark.Mikheev, Andrei. 2000. “Tagging sentenceboundaries.” In Proceedings of the FirstMeeting of the North American Chapter of theComputational Linguistics (NAACL’2000),pages 264–271, Seattle, Washington.Morgan Kaufmann.Mikheev, Andrei, Clair Grover, and ColinMatheson. 1998. TTT: Text Tokenisation Tool.Language Technology Group, Universityof Edinburgh. Available athttp://www.ltg.ed.ac.uk/software/ttt/index.html.Mikheev, Andrei, Clair Grover, and MarcMoens. 1998. Description of the ltgsystem used for MUC-7. In SeventhMessage Understanding Conference(MUC–7): Proceedings of a Conference Held inFairfax, Virginia. Morgan Kaufmann.Mikheev, Andrei and Liubov Liubushkina.1995. Russian morphology: Anengineering approach. Natural LanguageEngineering 1(3):235–260.Palmer, David D. and Marti A. Hearst. 1994.“Adaptive sentence boundarydisambiguation.” In Proceedings of theFourth ACL Conference on Applied NaturalLanguage Processing (ANLP’94), pages78–83, Stuttgart, Germany, October.Morgan Kaufmann.Palmer, David D. and Marti A. Hearst. 1997.Adaptive multilingual sentence boundarydisambiguation. Computational Linguistics23(2):241–269.Park, Youngja and Roy J. Byrd. 2001.“Hybrid text mining for findingabbreviations and their definitions.” InProceedings of the Conference on EmpiricalMethods in Natural Language Processing(EMLP’01), pages 16–19, Washington,D.C. Morgan Kaufmann.Ratnaparkhi, Adwait. 1996. “A maximumentropy model for part-of-speech317Computational Linguisticstagging.” In Proceedings of Conference onEmpirical Methods in Natural LanguageProcessing, pages 133–142, University ofPennsylvania, Philadelphia.Reynar, Jeffrey C. and Adwait Ratnaparkhi.1997. “A maximum entropy approach toidentifying sentence boundaries.” InProceedings of the Fifth ACL Conference onApplied Natural Language Processing(ANLP’97), pages 16–19. MorganKaufmann.Riley, Michael D. 1989. “Some applicationsof tree-based modeling to speech and318Volume 28, Number 3language indexing.” In Proceedings of theDARPA Speech and Natural LanguageWorkshop, pages 339–352. MorganKaufmann.Yarowsky, David. 1993. “One sense percollocation.” In Proceedings of ARPAHuman Language Technology Workshop ’93,pages 266–271, Princeton, New Jersey.Yarowsky, David. 1995. “Unsupervisedword sense disambiguation rivalingsupervised methods.” In Meeting of theAssociation for Computational Linguistics(ACL’95), pages 189–196. </biblio>
</article>
