<article>
 <preamble> probabilistic_sentence_reduction.pdf </preamble>
 <titre> Probabilistic Sentence Reduction Using Support Vector Machines  </titre>
 <auteur>                  Minh Le Nguyen, Akira Shimazu, Susumu Horiguchi                           Bao Tu Ho and Masaru Fukushi  </auteur>
 <abstract> Abstract This paper investigates a novel application of support vector machines (SVMs) for sentence reduction. We also propose a new probabilistic sentence reduction method based on support vector machine learning. Experimental results show that the proposed methods outperform earlier methods in term of sentence reduction performance.  1   </abstract>
 <biblio> ReferencesA. Borthwick, “A Maximum Entropy Approachto Named Entity Recognition”, Ph.D thesis, Computer Science Department, New YorkUniversity (1999).C.-C. Chang and C.-J. Lin,“LIBSVM: a library for support vector machines”, Software available athttp://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/ cjlin/libsvm.H. Jing, “Sentence reduction for automatictext summarization”, In Proceedings of theFirst Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics NAACL-2000.T.T. Hastie and R. Tibshirani, “Classificationby pairwise coupling”, The Annals of Statistics, 26(1): pp. 451-471, 1998.C.-W. Hsu and C.-J. Lin, “A comparison ofmethods for multi-class support vector machines”, IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks, 13, pp. 415-425, 2002.K. Knight and D. Marcu, “Summarization beyond sentence extraction: A Probabilistic approach to sentence compression”, ArtificialIntelligence 139: pp. 91-107, 2002.C.Y. Lin, “Improving Summarization Performance by Sentence Compression — A Pilot Study”, Proceedings of the Sixth International Workshop on Information Retrievalwith Asian Languages, pp.1-8, 2003.C. Macleod and R. Grishman, “COMMLEXsyntax Reference Manual”; Proteus Project,New York University (1995).M.L. Nguyen and S. Horiguchi, “A new sentencereduction based on Decision tree model”,Proceedings of 17th Pacific Asia Conferenceon Language, Information and Computation,pp. 290-297, 2003V. Vapnik, “The Natural of Statistical LearningTheory”, New York: Springer-Verlag, 1995.J. Platt,“ Probabilistic outputs for support vector machines and comparison to regularizedlikelihood methods,” in Advances in LargeMargin Classifiers, Cambridege, MA: MITPress, 2000.B. Scholkopf et al, “Comparing Support Vector Machines with Gausian Kernels to RadiusBasis Function Classifers”, IEEE Trans. Signal Procesing, 45, pp. 2758-2765, 1997. </biblio>
</article>
